export default {
  id: '1006_6_1a',
  name: '상용한자(6학년-1/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '刻', answer: ['새길 각', 'きざ(む)', 'こく'] },
    { question: '閣', answer: ['집 각', '집', 'かく'] },
    { question: '干', answer: ['방패 간', 'ほ(す)、ひ(る)', 'かん'] },
    { question: '看', answer: ['볼 간', '볼', 'かん'] },
    { question: '簡', answer: ['대쪽 간', '대쪽', 'かん'] },
    { question: '鋼', answer: ['강철 강', 'はがね', 'こう'] },
    { question: '降', answer: ['내릴 강', 'お(りる)、お(ろす)、ふ(る)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '激', answer: ['격할 격', 'はげ(しい)', 'げき'] },
    { question: '絹', answer: ['비단 견', 'きぬ', 'けん'] },
    { question: '敬', answer: ['공경 경', 'うやま(う)', 'けい'] },
    { question: '警', answer: ['경계할 경', '경계할', 'けい'] },
    { question: '届', answer: ['이를 계', 'とど(ける)、とど(く)', 'かい'] },
    { question: '系', answer: ['맬 계', '맬', 'けい'] },
    { question: '穀', answer: ['곡식 곡', '곡식', 'こく'] },
    { question: '困', answer: ['곤할 곤', 'こま(る)', 'こん'] },
    { question: '骨', answer: ['뼈 골', 'ほね', 'こつ'] },
    { question: '供', answer: ['이바지할 공', 'そな(える)、とも', 'きょう、[く]'] },
    { question: '権', answer: ['권세 권', '권세', 'けん、[ごん]'] },
    { question: '巻', answer: ['책 권', 'ま(く)、まき', 'かん'] },
    { question: '机', answer: ['책상 궤', 'つくえ', 'き'] },
    { question: '貴', answer: ['귀할 귀', 'とうと(い)、とうと(ぶ)、たっと(い)、たっと(ぶ)', 'き'] },
    { question: '劇', answer: ['심할 극', '심할', 'げき'] },
    { question: '勤', answer: ['부지런할 근', 'つと(める)、つと(まる)', 'きん、[ごん]'] },
    { question: '筋', answer: ['힘줄 근', 'すじ', 'きん'] },
    { question: '己', answer: ['몸 기', 'おのれ', 'こ、き'] },
    { question: '暖', answer: ['따뜻할 난', 'あたた(か)、あたた(かい)、あたた(まる)、あたた(める)', 'だん'] },
    { question: '難', answer: ['어려울 난', 'むずか(しい)、かた(い)', 'なん'] },
    { question: '納', answer: ['들일 납', 'おさ(める)、おさ(まる)', 'のう、[なっ]、[な]、[なん]、[とう]'] },
    { question: '脳', answer: ['골 뇌', '골', 'のう'] },
    { question: '段', answer: ['층계 단', '층계', 'だん'] },
    { question: '担', answer: ['멜 담', 'かつ(ぐ)、にな(う)', 'たん'] },
    { question: '党', answer: ['무리 당', '무리', 'とう'] },
    { question: '糖', answer: ['엿 당', '엿', 'とう'] },
    { question: '乱', answer: ['어지러울 란', 'みだ(れる)、みだ(す)', 'らん'] },
    { question: '覧', answer: ['볼 람', '볼', 'らん'] },
    { question: '卵', answer: ['알 란', 'たまご', 'らん'] },
    { question: '朗', answer: ['밝을 랑', 'ほが(らか)', 'ろう'] },
    { question: '論', answer: ['논할 론', '논할', 'ろん'] },
    { question: '律', answer: ['법칙 률', '법칙', 'りつ、[りち]'] },
    { question: '裏', answer: ['속 리', 'うら', 'り'] },
    { question: '臨', answer: ['임할 림', 'のぞ(む)', 'りん'] },
    { question: '幕', answer: ['장막 막', '장막', 'まく、ばく'] },
    { question: '晩', answer: ['늦을 만', '늦을', 'ばん'] },
    { question: '亡', answer: ['망할 망', 'な(い)', 'ぼう、[もう]'] },
    { question: '忘', answer: ['잊을 망', 'わす(れる)', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '枚', answer: ['낱 매', '낱', 'まい'] },
    { question: '盟', answer: ['맹세 맹', '맹세', 'めい'] },
    { question: '暮', answer: ['저물 모', 'く(れる)、く(らす)', 'ぼ'] },
    { question: '模', answer: ['본뜰 모', '본뜰', 'も、ぼ'] },
    { question: '密', answer: ['빽빽할 밀', '빽빽할', 'みつ'] },
    { question: '班', answer: ['나눌 반', '나눌', 'はん'] },
    { question: '訪', answer: ['찾을 방', 'おとず(れる)、たず(ねる)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '拝', answer: ['절 배', 'おが(む)', 'はい'] },
    { question: '背', answer: ['등 배', 'せ、せい、そむ(く)、そむ(ける)', 'はい'] },
    { question: '俳', answer: ['배우 배', '배우', 'はい'] },
    { question: '並', answer: ['나란히 병', 'なみ、なら(べる)、なら(ぶ)、なら(びに)', 'へい'] },
    { question: '補', answer: ['기울 보', 'おぎな(う)', 'ほ'] },
    { question: '宝', answer: ['보배 보', 'たから', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '腹', answer: ['배 복', 'はら', 'ふく'] },
    { question: '棒', answer: ['막대 봉', '막대', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '否', answer: ['아닐 부', 'いな', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '奮', answer: ['떨칠 분', 'ふる(う)', 'ふん'] },
    { question: '秘', answer: ['숨길 비', 'ひ(める)', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '批', answer: ['비평할 비', '비평할', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '私', answer: ['사사 사', 'わたくし、わたし', 'し'] },
    { question: '砂', answer: ['모래 사', 'すな', 'さ、しゃ'] },
    { question: '詞', answer: ['말 사', '말', 'し'] },
    { question: '捨', answer: ['버릴 사', 'す(てる)', 'しゃ'] },
    { question: '射', answer: ['쏠 사', 'い(る)', 'しゃ'] },
    { question: '傷', answer: ['다칠 상', 'きず、いた(む)、いた(める)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '署', answer: ['마을 서', '마을', 'しょ'] },
    { question: '善', answer: ['착할 선', 'よ(い)', 'ぜん'] },
    { question: '宣', answer: ['베풀 선', '베풀', 'せん'] },
    { question: '城', answer: ['재 성', 'しろ', 'じょう'] },
    { question: '盛', answer: ['성할 성', 'も(る)、さか(る)、さか(ん)', 'せい、[じょう]'] },
    { question: '聖', answer: ['성인 성', '성인', 'せい'] },
    { question: '誠', answer: ['정성 성', 'まこと', 'せい'] },
    { question: '洗', answer: ['씻을 세', 'あら(う)', 'せん'] },
    { question: '垂', answer: ['드리울 수', 'た(れる)、た(らす)', 'すい'] },
    { question: '収', answer: ['거둘 수', 'おさ(まる)、おさ(める)', 'しゅう'] },
    { question: '樹', answer: ['나무 수', '나무', 'じゅ'] },
    { question: '熟', answer: ['익을 숙', 'う(れる)', 'じゅく'] },
    { question: '純', answer: ['순수할 순', '순수할', 'じゅん'] },
    { question: '視', answer: ['볼 시', '볼', 'し'] },
    { question: '我', answer: ['나 아', 'われ、わ', 'が'] },
    { question: '若', answer: ['같을 약', 'わか(い)、も(しくは)', 'じゃく、[にゃく]'] },
    { question: '厳', answer: ['엄할 엄', 'おごそ(か)、きび(しい)', 'げん、[ごん]'] },
    { question: '域', answer: ['지경 역', '지경', 'いき'] },
    { question: '訳', answer: ['번역할 역', 'わけ', 'やく'] },
    { question: '延', answer: ['늘일 연', 'の(びる)、の(べる)、の(ばす)', 'えん'] }
  ]
}
